League of Women Voters of Saratoga County; Records apap339
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
League of Women Voters of Saratoga County Records1965-2010
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
League of Women Voters of Saratoga County (Saratoga County, N.Y.)
apap339
4.2 cubic ft.
Founded in 1920, the League of Women Voters is a nonpartisan political organization that informs citizens about government, encourages their participation, and seeks to influence public policy through education and advocacy. One of nearly 60 local leagues in New York State, the League of Women Voters of Saratoga County (formerly the League of Women Voters, Saratoga Springs Area) formed in early 1965. This collection documents the operation and activities of this local league from its founding through 2010.
Access
Access to this record group is unrestricted.
Acquisition Information
Initial items in this collection were donated to the University Libraries, M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections and Archives, by former longtime LWVSC president Barbara Thomas, July 15, 2013.
Barbara Thomas donated additional materials, November 2, 2015.
Organizational Sketch
The (National) League of Women Voters (LWV) was founded by Carrie Chapman Catt in 1920 during the convention of the National American Woman Suffrage Association. The convention was held just six months before the 19th amendment to the U.S. Constitution was ratified, giving women the right to vote after a 72-year struggle.
The League began as a "mighty political experiment" designed to help 20 million women carry out their new responsibilities as voters. It encouraged them to use their new power to participate in shaping public policy. From the beginning, the League has been an activist, grassroots organization whose leaders believed that citizens should play a critical role in advocacy. The League is proud to be nonpartisan, neither supporting nor opposing candidates or political parties at any level of government, but always working on vital issues of concern to members and the public.
The League, now open to men and women, has 150,000 plus members, and supporters in the U.S., with Leagues in every state, Puerto Rico, Washington, D.C., the Virgin Islands and Hong Kong. Statewide in New York, there are nearly 60 local leagues with approximately 8000 members.
The Saratoga County Chapter was founded in 1965, as a "provisional league," under the name of League of Women Voters of the Saratoga Springs Area. At the time, with the exception of Saratoga Springs, most of Saratoga County consisted of small towns and farming areas, with some residents of the southern portion of the county having closer ties to the Schenectady County Chapter of the league. Thus it was decided to make Saratoga Springs the hub of this new chapter, specifically including the towns of Saratoga Springs, Wilton and Greenfield. To fulfill national requirements, a thorough study of the community was prepared early in 1965, and members were recruited to meet the 25 member minimum. The chapter was granted authority from the national organization in early 1965, and had its first organizational meeting on April 8, 1965. A membership total of 59 was reported at the April 28, 1965 board meeting. In April, 1967 the organization was granted "full league" status.
In 1999, with the demise of the Southern Saratoga County LWV (previously know as the Shenendehowa LWV), it was decided to apply for expansion to include the whole county in the organization. Permission was granted by the national LWV on February 17, 2000 for the name change to League of Women Voters of Saratoga County (LWVSC). Members of disbanded chapters were invited to join. (Records of the LWV of Southern Saratoga County are not included in the collection.)
Since 2000, the LWVSC has expanded its activities and membership to serve the whole county. The 2010-2011 membership list includes approximately 160 members.
The stated mission of the LWVSC, like its parent organization, is as follows: The League of Women Voters, a nonpartisan political organization, encourages informed and active participation in government, works to increase understanding of major public policy issues, and influences public policy through education and advocacy.
The information provided above was gleaned from the following sources:
Scope and Contents
This collection contains the records of the League of Women Voters of Saratoga County (LWVSC), from its founding in 1965 through 2010. It documents the organization's internal functioning and its public activities during that time. Included are the administrative documents of the chapter: by-laws and revisions, membership and officer lists, annual reports, annual meeting program information, some correspondence, budget and financial statements, monthly meeting minutes, and monthly member bulletins (newsletters). Information on the work of the chapter in education, outreach and advocacy projects is detailed by project, and includes meeting notes, studies, reports, surveys, photographs and news clippings. In addition to the newsletters, there are various other publications the league sponsored. Also included are a small number of videotapes, mainly of local "Meet the Candidate" events.
While records of the disbanded LWV of Southern Saratoga County are not included in the collection, the Project and Subject Files contain a few projects in which this group participated, and a Clifton Park-Halfmoon Community Study from 1971, apparently prepared for purposes of securing provisional league status for that organization.
The archivist retained file titles created by the League of Women Voters of Saratoga County.
Researchers also may wish to consult the League of Women Voters of Albany County Records (APAP-128), the League of Women Voters of Rensselaer County Records (APAP-103) and the League of Women Voters of Schenectady County Records (APAP-210) held by the Department of Special Collections and Archives.
Arrangement of the Collection
The collection is organized into the following series:
Women; Social Activists and Public Advocates; Public Servants; Politics and Politicians; Education; Election law--New York (State); Elections--New York (State); Local government--New York (State); Political planning--New York (State); Voter registration--New York (State); Voting--New York (State); Women--New York (State)--Saratoga County--Societies and clubs; Women in nonprofit organizations--New York (State)--Saratoga County; Women political activists--New York (State)--Saratoga County; Administrative records; Annual reports; Clippings; Correspondence; Financial Records; Minutes; Membership; Newsletters; Photographs; Programs (documents); Studies; Videotapes; League of Women Voters (U.S.); League of Women Voters of New York State; League of Women Voters of Saratoga County (Saratoga County, N.Y.)
- Administrative Files, 1965-2010; 1; 1.8 cubic ft.
  Arrangement
  Arranged chronologically.
  Scope and Contents
  The Administrative Files series consists of organizational records which document the activities of the Board of Directors. These include founding documents, by-laws and changes, annual reports to the national organization, monthly meeting minutes, and event programs from annual chapter meetings. Budgets, treasurer reports and event calendars are mainly interfiled with meeting minutes, as is some correspondence. There are gaps in some months and years. Files labeled "Other" contain a mixture of items, including correspondence, budgets, pamphlets, Voters Guides, annual program calendar flyers and study reports.
  - Bylaws, 1965 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 1965 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 2)
  - Organizational Meeting and Study, 1965 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 3)
  - Budgets, 1965-1989 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 4)
  - Membership Lists, 1965-1991 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 1966 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 6)
  - Fund Drive Letters, 1966-1968; 1970-1971; Undated (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 7)
  - Observer Corps, 1966-1968; 1980; Undated (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 8)
  - Committee Lists, 1966; 1981; 1987-1988 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 9)
  - Bylaws, 1967 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 10)
  - Minutes, 1967 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 11)
  - Minutes, 1968 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 12)
  - Other, 1968 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 13)
  - Finance Drives, 1968-1979; 1981-1990 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 14)
  - Minutes, 1969 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 15)
  - 1969-1970 Annual Report, ca. 1969 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 16)
  - Other, 1969; Undated (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 17)
  - Board Lists, 1969-1971; 1981-1983; 1985-1989 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 18)
  - 1970-1971 Annual Report (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 19)
  - Minutes, 1970 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 20)
  - Other, 1970 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 21)
  - Correspondence, 1970-1975 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 22)
  - Membership Lists, 1970-1971; 1973-1975 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 23)
  - Minutes, 1971 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 24)
  - 1971-1972 Annual Report, ca. 1971 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 25)
  - Bylaw Changes, 1971; 1973 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 26)
  - Minutes, 1972 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 27)
  - 1972-1973 Annual Report (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 28)
  - Minutes, 1973 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 29)
  - 1973-1974 Annual Report, ca. 1973 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 30)
  - Minutes, 1974 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 31)
  - 1974-1975 Annual Report, ca. 1974 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 32)
  - Minutes, 1975 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 32)
  - Minutes, 1976; Undated (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 34)
  - Membership Lists, 1976-1980 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 35)
  - Correspondence, 1976; 1980; 1982; 1985-1987; 1989 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 36)
  - Minutes, 1977 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 37)
  - Treasurer's Report, 1977-1984 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 38)
  - Minutes, 1978 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 39)
  - Minutes, 1979 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 40)
  - Annual Meeting Booklets, 1979-1981; 1984-1987; 1989; 1991-1995 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 41)
  - Minutes, 1980 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 42)
  - Other, 1980 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 43)
  - Minutes, 1981 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 44)
  - Membership Lists, 1981-1985 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 45)
  - Minutes, 1982 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 46)
  - Minutes, 1983 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 47)
  - Other, 1983; Undated (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 48)
  - Minutes, 1984 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 49)
  - Minutes, 1985 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 50)
  - Minutes, 1986 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 51)
  - Membership Lists, 1986-1990 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 52)
  - Bylaws and Revisions, 1987 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 53)
  - Minutes, 1987 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 54)
  - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 55)
  - Minutes, 1988 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 56)
  - Bylaws Revised, 1989 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 57)
  - Minutes, 1989 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 58)
  - Correspondence, 1989; Undated (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 59)
  - Financial Reports, 1988-1990 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 60)
  - Minutes, 1990 (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 61)
  - Correspondence, 1990; Undated (Box 1 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 62)
  - Minutes, 1991 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 1)
  - Membership Lists, 1991-1995 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 2)
  - Bylaws, 1992 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1992 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 1992 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1993 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 1994 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 1994; Undated (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 1995 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 10)
  - Minutes, 1995 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 11)
  - Correspondence, 1996 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 12)
  - Minutes, 1996; Undated (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 13)
  - Membership Lists, 1996-1999 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 14)
  - Minutes, 1997 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 15)
  - Annual Meeting Booklets, 1997-2000 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 16)
  - Minutes, 1998; Undated (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 17)
  - Minutes, 1999; Undated (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 18)
  - Name Change to LWV of Saratoga County, 1999-2000; Undated (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 19)
  - Bylaws, 2000 (Box 2 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 20)
  - Minutes, 2000 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 1)
  - Membership Lists, 2000; 2002-2005 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 2001 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 3)
  - Annual Meeting Booklets, 2001-2005 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 2002 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 2003; Undated (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 2004; Undated (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 2005 (Box 3 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 8)
  - Tax Status, 2005 (Box 4 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 2006 (Box 4 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 2)
  - Annual Meeting Booklets, 2006-2010 (Box 4 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 3)
  - Membership Lists, 2006-2010 (Box 4 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 4)
  - Bylaws, 2007 (Box 4 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 2007 (Box 4 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 2008; Undated (Box 4 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 2009; Undated (Box 4 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 8)
  - Minutes, 2010 (Box 4 (1-Administrative Files), Folder 9)
- Publications, 1965-2010; 2; 1.0 cubic ft.
  This series consists mainly of the monthly bulletins that were sent to LWVSC members and select members of the public. Each one contains a message from the President, information about chapter events, as well as state and national LWV news and conventions. They also inform members of meetings, candidate events, studies and advocacy projects and voter registration information. There are some missing months. Other publications in this series are Community Guides, Voters Guides and various booklets and pamphlets.
  - Bulletins, 1965 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 1)
  - Bulletins, 1966 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 2)
  - A Citizen's Guide to Saratoga Springs, 1967 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 3)
  - Bulletins, 1967 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 4)
  - Voter's Guides, 1967-1968 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 5)
  - Bulletins, 1968 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 6)
  - Bulletins, 1969 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 7)
  - Bulletins, 1970 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 8)
  - Miscellaneous, 1970; 1980-1985; 1987; 1994; Undated (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 9)
  - Voter's Guides, 1970; 1974 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 10)
  - Bulletins, 1971 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 11)
  - Bulletins, 1972 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 12)
  - Bulletins, 1973 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 13)
  - Bulletins, 1974 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 14)
  - Bulletins, 1975 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 15)
  - Voter's Guides, 1975 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 16)
  - Bulletins, 1976 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 17)
  - Voter's Guides, 1976-1978 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 18)
  - Bulletins, 1977 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 19)
  - Bulletins, 1978 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 20)
  - Bulletins, 1979 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 21)
  - Bulletins, 1980 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 22)
  - Community Guides, 1980; Undated (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 23)
  - Voter's Guides, 1980; 1983 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 24)
  - Bulletins, 1981 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 25)
  - Study of Saratoga Springs School District, 1981; 1983-1984 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 26)
  - Bulletins, 1982 (Box 1 (2-Publications), Folder 27)
  - Bulletins, 1983 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 1)
  - Bulletins, 1984 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 2)
  - In League with Eleanor by Hilda Watrous, 1984 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 3)
  - Bulletins, 1985 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 4)
  - Bulletins, 1986 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 5)
  - Bulletins, 1987 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 6)
  - Bulletins, 1988 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 7)
  - Bulletins, 1989 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 8)
  - Bulletins, 1990 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 9)
  - Bulletins, 1991 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 10)
  - Bulletins, 1992 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 11)
  - Bulletins, 1993 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 12)
  - Bulletins, 1994 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 13)
  - Bulletins, 1995 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 14)
  - Bulletins, 1996 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 15)
  - Bulletins, 1997 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 16)
  - Bulletins, 1998 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 17)
  - Bulletins, 1999 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 18)
  - Bulletins, 2000 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 19)
  - Bulletins, 2001 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 20)
  - Bulletins, 2002 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 21)
  - Bulletins, 2003 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 22)
  - Bulletins, 2004 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 23)
  - Bulletins, 2005 (Box 2 (2-Publications), Folder 24)
  - Bulletins, 2006 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 1)
  - Bulletins, 2007 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 2)
  - Bulletins, 2008 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 3)
  - Bulletins, 2009 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 4)
  - Bulletins, 2010 (Box 3 (2-Publications), Folder 5)
- Project and Subject Files, 1968-2010; 3; 1.4 cubic ft.
  Arranged alphabetically.
  This series contains the records of major projects undertaken by the League, starting with Saratoga Springs City Charter Activities (1968 to 1980s) to the Famous Person Fundraisers (2006-2010). Other significant topics include: Emergency Services Study, Elder Services Program, Polling Place Accessibility Studies, Russian Delegation visits, and Student Voting Rights. These project files contain program descriptions, grant applications, studies, surveys, reports, news clippings, and photographs (unlabeled). Also included in this series are 13 videotapes of chapter events from 2001-2008.
  - 75th Anniversary of LWVNY, 1994 (Box 1 (3-Project and Subject Files), Folder 1)
  - 75th Anniversary of LWVUS - Special Cancellation, 1995 (Box 1 (3-Project and Subject Files), Folder 2)
  - 75th Anniversary of LWVUS - "The Stone that Started the Ripple", 1995; Undated (Box 1 (3-Project and Subject Files), Folder 3)
  - 1928 Press Release for Kathryn Starbuck and LWVNY, Undated (Box 1 (3-Project and Subject Files), Folder 4)
  - Alternatives to Incarceration Consensus, 1992; Undated (Box 1 (3-Project and Subject Files), Folder 5)
  - Balancing Justice Project, 1999-2000 (Box 1 (3-Project and Subject Files), Folder 6)
  - Candidate Events, 1970-1986; 1989 (Box 1 (3-Project and Subject Files), Folder 7)
  - Clifton Park Community Study, 1971 (Box 1 (3-Project and Subject Files), Folder 8)
  - Constitution Day, 2008 (Video-tape 1)
  - Constitution Day - Grant Application, 2008 (Box 1 (3-Project and Subject Files), Folder 9)
  - Constitution Day - Evaluation Forms, 2008 (Box 1 (3-Project and Subject Files), Folder 10)
  - Constitution Day - Program Planning and Publicity, 2008 (Box 1 (3-Project and Subject Files), Folder 11)
  - Constitution Day - Report, 2008 (Box 1 (3-Project and Subject Files), Folder 12)
  - Daycare Survey and Report, 1969; Undated (Box 1 (3-Project and Subject Files), Folder 13)
  - Day Care, 1985-1991 (Box 1 (3-Project and Subject Files), Folder 14)
  - Death Penalty - David Kaczynski, Presenter, 2005 January 27 (Video-tape 2)
  - Drug Law Reform, 2001 June 14 (Video-tape 3)
  - Emergency Services Study - Background, 1999-2000 (Box 1 (3-Project and Subject Files), Folder 15)
  - Emergency Services Study - Consensus and Position, 2000; Undated (Box 1 (3-Project and Subject Files), Folder 16)
  - Emergency Services Study - Meetings, 1998-1999; Undated (Box 1 (3-Project and Subject Files), Folder 17)
  - Emergency Services Study - Meeting and Study Materials, 1996-1997; Undated (Box 1 (3-Project and Subject Files), Folder 18)
  - Emergency Services Study - Questionnaires, 1999-2000 (Box 1 (3-Project and Subject Files), Folder 19)
  - Emergency Services Study - News Clippings, 1998-1999 (Box 1 (3-Project and Subject Files), Folder 20)
  - Emergency Services Study - Numbering Procedures for 911 Service, 1996 (Box 1 (3-Project and Subject Files), Folder 21)
  - Expanded In-Home Services for the Elderly Program (EISEP) - Advocacy Materials, 1989-1990 (Box 1 (3-Project and Subject Files), Folder 22)
  - Expanded In-Home Services for the Elderly Program (EISEP) - Correspondence, 1989-1990; Undated (Box 1 (3-Project and Subject Files), Folder 23)
  - Expanded In-Home Services for the Elderly Program (EISEP) - Articles and Notes, 1988; 1990-1991; Undated (Box 1 (3-Project and Subject Files), Folder 24)
  - Expanded In-Home Services for the Elderly Program (EISEP) - Description of Programs, Undated (Box 1 (3-Project and Subject Files), Folder 25)
  - Expanded In-Home Services for the Elderly Program (EISEP) - Letters of Support, 1990; Undated (Box 1 (3-Project and Subject Files), Folder 26)
  - Expanded In-Home Services for the Elderly Program (EISEP) - Need Report, 1989 (Box 1 (3-Project and Subject Files), Folder 27)
  - Expanded In-Home Services for the Elderly Program (EISEP) - Newsclippings, 1990 (Box 1 (3-Project and Subject Files), Folder 28)
  - Expanded In-Home Services for the Elderly Program (EISEP) - Personnel and Advocate Lists, 1990; Undated (Box 1 (3-Project and Subject Files), Folder 29)
  - Economic Opportunity Council (EOC) Elections Part 1, 1968; 1973; Undated (Box 1 (3-Project and Subject Files), Folder 30)
  - Economic Opportunity Council (EOC) Elections Part 2, 1981-1982; Undated (Box 1 (3-Project and Subject Files), Folder 31)
  - Famous Person Celebration - Elizabeth Cady Stanton, 2010 (Box 1 (3-Project and Subject Files), Folder 32)
  - Famous Person Fundraiser - Abraham Lincoln, 2009-2010; Undated (Box 1 (3-Project and Subject Files), Folder 33)
  - Famous Person Fundraiser - Abraham Lincoln - Lincoln Coin Sets, 2010 (Artifact-box 1)
  - Famous Person Fundraiser - Abraham Lincoln - Photos, 2010 (Dvd 1)
  - Famous Person Fundraiser - Eleanor Roosevelt, 2006 (Box 1 (3-Project and Subject Files), Folder 34)
  - Famous Person Fundraiser - Susan B. Anthony, 2009 (Box 1 (3-Project and Subject Files), Folder 35)
  - Famous Person Fundraiser - Susan B. Anthony - "Only the Message Mattered", 2009 (Cd 1)
  - Focus on the Poor - Saratoga County Publication, 1973 (Box 1 (3-Project and Subject Files), Folder 36)
  - Focus on the Poor - Study Materials and Correspondence, 1972-1974 (Box 1 (3-Project and Subject Files), Folder 37)
  - Forum on Federal Budget Cuts, 1981; 1989 (Box 1 (3-Project and Subject Files), Folder 38)